Ishan Raj Jain

PHONE: +919650073354 EMAIL: ishanjain1991@gmail.com GITHUB: https://github.com/inuishan TWITTER: https://twitter.com/ishanjain_t

I am a backend software engineer with 4+ years experience, looking for a creative work environment with learning opportunities. I have worked with high volumes of data in low latency systems for big enterprises. I have been an important part of two startups till now where I was involved in complete lifecycle of the product.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Current JUNE 2016

Founding Member, Morph.ai, Gurgaon

- · Led backend.
 - Built the technology from ground up.
 - Built a **low latency** chatbot framework to listen messages from social channel, augment it with our analysis engine and run the business defined conversation logic.
 - Wrote analytics engine which helped improve the bot performance for Mancity.
 - Wrote **performance crucial** announcement engine which is being used by Mancity to send matchday updates to thousands of subscribers in realtime.
 - Wrote custom code module with language support of Java and Python using AWS Lambda which helped YES Bank to build their bot.
- · Led Dev-Ops.
 - Automated deployment using Jenkins.
 - Wrote server setup scripts for over 14 different types of servers to get the new machines running in seconds.
 - Setup mongo cluster with LVM based daily backup, ElasticSearch cluster & Redis standalone server.
 - Improved security using firewall rules.

JAN 2014 - JUNE 2016

Senior Product Engineer, Sprinklr Solutions (April 2015 - June 2016)

- Led Analytics module comprising a team of 12 developers.
- Used ElasticSearch to aggregate millions of documents in real time with custom aggregators.
- Built email auto responder with Salesforce integration for Procter & Gamble using SVM and a neural network model which saved them ~\$5 per email.
- Built a generic SLA measurement rule engine & analytic tool for JPMorgan Chase which helped them reduce response time for crucial messages.
- Built Autoscheduler and Resonance Meter while posting a social media update which contributed to Sprinklr coming out as a leader in **Forrester** wave 2015.

Product Engineer, Sprinklr Solutions (Jan 2014 - April 2015)

- Salesforce integration for creation of cases from social messages.
- Involved in migrating Mongo based analytics solution to ElasticSearch which drastically reduced the query response times.

EDUCATION

JULY 2010

B.Tech in Computer Science, Dhirubhai Ambani Institute, Gandhinagar

- MAY 2014
- CPI 8.44/10
- Research assistant for Cross Lingual Information Access project by Information Retrieval Society of India.
- Project aimed at making search engine using Solr for Indian languages.
- Founder & convener, Artificial Intelligence Club.

SKILLS, LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

Java, Python (Intermediatory)

Mongo, ElasticSearch, Redis, SQL, Spring, Mesos, Spark, Linux, Jenkins, Artificial Intelligence